# Nada Mostafa

**Data Science Pre-Master Student with Teaching Assistant Experience** 

Cairo, Egypt (+20) 1143238354 nadam4943@gmail.com **Linkedin** 

#### **ABOUT**

Experienced Teaching Assistant and Data Science Enthusiast. As a pre-master's student in Data Science at Helwan University, I've honed my skills in data analysis and application development. My teaching assistant experience has strengthened my ability to communicate complex concepts effectively. I'm proficient in Python and SQL and have practical experience with Android development and UI/UX design. My passion for learning and staying updated with industry trends drives my continuous professional growth.

#### **EDUCATION**

Helwan University, Cairo, Egypt - Master of Data Science - ( January 2024-Present)

Canadian International College, Cairo, Egypt — Bachelor of Computer Science (2019-2023) Mobile and Cloud Computing Major GPA: 3.83/4.00

## **RESEARCH PAPERS**

Nada M. Ali , Samar K. Mohamed , Dalia Magdi , "Comparative Evaluation of Software Composition Analysis Tools in the Context of Technical Debt Reduction ", INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE OF TECHNICAL DEBT AND SOFTWARE COMPOSITION ANALYSIS: "A MULTI DISCIPLINARY APPROACH" , ( Also submitted in a journal for review )

Abdallah Bahaa , Nada Mostafa , Abdelrahman Medhat , Moaz Ahmed , Mostafa Ahmed , Mariam M. Abdellatif , Sara Abdelghafar , "Smart E-Learning Platform: Enhancing Learning Experience using Recommendation-Based Content and Collaborative Filtering with XAPI Integration " ( submitted for review )

### **EXPERIENCE**

CIC (Canadian International College), New Cairo — Teaching Assistant - Oct 2023 - July 2024

- Provided guidance and support to computer science students in various programming concepts
- Provided academic advising, administrative support, and systematic scheduling input to computer science students
- Organized and facilitated a VR workshop for computer science students that focused on hands-on experimentation with VR technology, allowing students to explore its potential applications in
- Contributed to the organization of a week-long event for students helping the students to discover their career potentials and get insights from industry professionals.

E-Shire Technology, Remote — Software Engineer - Oct 2023 - Nov 2023

• Responsible for developing applications that meet the highest quality standards.

EFE Egypt, Almaza — Trainee - Sep 2022 - Sep 2022

Entrepreneurship program providing business startup and management skills .

Ministry of Communications and Information Technology, Smart Village - Trainee - JUNE 2022 - Aug 2022

5 weeks of instruction in infrastructure, systems, applications and cyber security.

Artronix — Mobile development - Trainee - Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

Two months of training in android development with Java programming language.

CIB — Trainee - JUL 2021 - Aug 2021

3 weeks of financial inclusion training understanding individuals and businesses.

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Python For Data Science(Certificate)
- Machine Learning Fundamentals with Python(Certificate)
- Deep Learning in Python(Certificate)
- Udacity Advanced Android Development NANODEGREE(Certificate)
- Udemy Web Development Bootcamp(Certificate)
- UI/UX Design(<u>Certificate</u>) Machine Learning (<u>Certificate</u>)

#### **SKILLS**

#### Soft Skills:

- Teaching
- Communication
- Presentation
- Time Management
- Risk Management
- Problem Solving
- Creative Thinking
- Disciplined
- Organization

#### Hard Skills:

- Data Analysis
- Excel
- Power Bi
- Python
- SOL
- Machine Learning
- Software Development
- C++, Java, Kotlin
- HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Mobile Development With Kotlin/Java
- Project Management
- Microsoft Project UI/ UX Design
- Adobe XD
- Figma

## **LANGUAGES**

- Arabic-Mother Tongue
- English-Fluent

## **GRADUATION PROJECT**

- Title: "Aiming" (A Smart E-learning Platform in the form of a website that works as a recommender system uses student activity data and historical enrollments to suggest learning materials, while offering instructors tools for content creation and assessment)
- Tools used: Machine learning, Flask Framework, XAPI, Python, HTML, CSS.
- Grade: A+